class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> post_harvest_technology = [


  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of post-harvest technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase crop yield",
        "B. Enhance shelf life and quality of produce",
        "C. Accelerate the growth of crops",
        "D. Improve soil fertility"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest technology focuses on preserving the quality and extending the shelf life of agricultural produce, ensuring its freshness and market value.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following is a post-harvest storage method for grains?",
      options: [
        "A. Refrigeration",
        "B. Silo storage",
        "C. Sun drying",
        "D. Composting"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Silo storage is a common method for storing grains post-harvest, providing a controlled environment to prevent spoilage and maintain quality.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What role does ethylene play in post-harvest ripening of fruits?",
      options: [
        "A. Inhibits ripening",
        "B. Accelerates ripening",
        "C. Has no effect on ripening",
        "D. Causes decay"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Ethylene is a plant hormone that accelerates the ripening process in fruits, making it crucial in post-harvest handling and storage.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. Which of the following is a post-harvest pest control method?",
      options: [
        "A. Genetic modification",
        "B. Pesticide application",
        "C. Crop rotation",
        "D. Organic farming"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Pesticide application is a common post-harvest method to control pests and prevent damage to stored agricultural products.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the purpose of post-harvest washing of vegetables and fruits?",
      options: [
        "A. Improve taste",
        "B. Remove soil and contaminants",
        "C. Enhance color",
        "D. Increase vitamin content"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest washing is done to remove soil, contaminants, and pesticide residues from the surface of fruits and vegetables, ensuring food safety and quality.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. Which atmospheric gas is often controlled in controlled atmosphere storage?",
      options: [
        "A. Oxygen",
        "B. Nitrogen",
        "C. Carbon dioxide",
        "D. Hydrogen"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Controlled atmosphere storage regulates the levels of oxygen, carbon dioxide, and nitrogen to slow down the ripening and aging processes, extending the shelf life of produce.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the main purpose of post-harvest drying of crops?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhance flavor",
        "B. Reduce moisture content",
        "C. Increase vitamin content",
        "D. Improve color"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest drying is performed to reduce the moisture content of crops, preventing mold growth and extending storage life.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. Which post-harvest technology is used to remove excess moisture from food products?",
      options: [
        "A. Refrigeration",
        "B. Freeze drying",
        "C. Fermentation",
        "D. Irradiation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Freeze drying is a method of post-harvest technology that removes excess moisture from food products, preserving them for longer periods without the need for refrigeration.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the purpose of post-harvest fumigation?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhance flavor",
        "B. Control pests and pathogens",
        "C. Improve texture",
        "D. Increase nutritional content"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest fumigation is conducted to control pests and pathogens in stored agricultural products, preventing spoilage and ensuring product quality.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. Which post-harvest technology is commonly used for the preservation of fruits and vegetables by removing microorganisms?",
      options: [
        "A. Canning",
        "B. Irradiation",
        "C. Dehydration",
        "D. Fermentation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Irradiation is a post-harvest technology that involves exposing fruits and vegetables to ionizing radiation, effectively removing microorganisms and extending shelf life.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. What is the primary purpose of post-harvest grading?",
      options: [
        "A. Determine moisture content",
        "B. Assess nutritional value",
        "C. Classify products based on quality",
        "D. Increase shelf life"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest grading is performed to classify agricultural products based on quality, helping in marketing and ensuring consumers receive products of a consistent standard.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. Which storage condition is crucial for preventing the sprouting of potatoes during post-harvest storage?",
      options: [
        "A. High humidity",
        "B. Low temperature",
        "C. Excess sunlight",
        "D. Adequate ventilation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Maintaining low temperatures is crucial in preventing the sprouting of potatoes during post-harvest storage, as it inhibits the physiological processes that lead to sprouting.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. What is the primary objective of post-harvest transportation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase crop yield",
        "B. Minimize post-harvest losses",
        "C. Enhance flavor",
        "D. Accelerate ripening"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'The main goal of post-harvest transportation is to minimize post-harvest losses by ensuring the efficient and timely delivery of agricultural products to markets or processing facilities.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. Which of the following post-harvest technologies is used to control the ripening of fruits?",
      options: [
        "A. Controlled atmosphere storage",
        "B. Ethylene application",
        "C. Freeze drying",
        "D. Canning"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Controlled atmosphere storage is a technology that regulates environmental factors like temperature, humidity, and gases to control the ripening process of fruits during storage.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. What is the purpose of post-harvest waxing of certain fruits?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhance aroma",
        "B. Increase weight",
        "C. Improve appearance and shelf life",
        "D. Reduce ripening time"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest waxing is done to improve the appearance and shelf life of certain fruits by providing a protective layer, reducing moisture loss, and enhancing visual appeal.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. Which post-harvest technology involves the removal of water from food products using high temperatures?",
      options: [
        "A. Dehydration",
        "B. Irradiation",
        "C. Canning",
        "D. Controlled atmosphere storage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Dehydration is a post-harvest technology that involves the removal of water from food products using high temperatures, preserving the products for extended storage.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. What is the primary purpose of post-harvest packaging?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhance flavor",
        "B. Reduce weight",
        "C. Prevent spoilage and damage",
        "D. Increase nutritional content"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest packaging is designed to prevent spoilage and damage during transportation and storage, maintaining the quality and freshness of agricultural products.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. Which post-harvest technology involves the application of microorganisms to enhance the flavor, texture, or nutritional value of food products?",
      options: [
        "A. Freeze drying",
        "B. Fermentation",
        "C. Canning",
        "D. Controlled atmosphere storage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Fermentation is a post-harvest technology that involves the controlled application of microorganisms to food products, leading to changes in flavor, texture, and nutritional content.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. What is the primary purpose of post-harvest irradiation?",
      options: [
        "A. Control pests",
        "B. Enhance color",
        "C. Reduce moisture content",
        "D. Increase shelf life"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Post-harvest irradiation is primarily used to control pests in stored agricultural products, preventing infestations and maintaining product quality.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. Which post-harvest technology is commonly used for preserving meat and seafood?",
      options: [
        "A. Freeze drying",
        "B. Canning",
        "C. Refrigeration",
        "D. Controlled atmosphere storage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Canning is a widely used post-harvest technology for preserving meat and seafood by sealing them in airtight containers, preventing spoilage and bacterial contamination.'
  ),

];